Okay Katherine.
好的，凱瑟琳。
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm. &gt;&gt; We hit the plus sign.
&gt;&gt;嗯。 &gt;&gt;我們按下「加號」。
[SOUND] And the number of cups of coffee goes up from two to three.
[聲音]咖啡杯數由二加至三。
&gt;&gt; Okay. &gt;&gt; But we keep hitting the plus sign.
&gt;&gt;好的。 &gt;&gt;我們繼續按「加號」。
[SOUND] Again.
[聲音]再一次。
[SOUND] And the number of cups of coffee just stays at two, it's not going up.
[聲音]而咖啡的杯數 停留在二，無上升。
&gt;&gt; Okay, well I think it's because we're missing one concept, and
&gt;&gt;好的，我認為這是因為 我們缺少一個概念，
that is variable scope.
就是變數的可視範圍。
&gt;&gt; Variable scope?
&gt;&gt;變數的可視範圍？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt;對呀。
&gt;&gt; Care to explain?
&gt;&gt;希望解釋嗎？
&gt;&gt; Variable scope means that when a variable is declared in a method,
&gt;&gt;變數的可視範圍即是， 當一個變數在方法中宣告，
it can be only used in the scope of that method.
它只可於那方法範圍內使用。
&gt;&gt; [SOUND] &gt;&gt; Pay attention.
&gt;&gt; [聲音] &gt;&gt;要注意。
&gt;&gt; Katherine.
&gt;&gt;凱瑟琳。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. &gt;&gt; We're talking in gibberish.
&gt;&gt;對呀。 &gt;&gt;我們正在胡言亂語。
Someone needs to give students in this class a medal for
有人需要給這個課程的學生一枚獎章
getting this far ahead.
因為他們已學到這麼多。
&gt;&gt; Okay. &gt;&gt; Let's slow down and explain clearly.
&gt;&gt;好的。 &gt;&gt;讓我們慢下來，解釋清楚。
&gt;&gt; Sorry. Okay, I can explain.
&gt;&gt;對不起。 好的，我可以解釋。
&gt;&gt; Okay, so we hit the plus button.
&gt;&gt;好的，我們按下「加號」按鈕。
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm. &gt;&gt; And the increment method inside
&gt;&gt;嗯。 &gt;&gt;代碼裡的增量方法
a code gets called.
被呼叫。
&gt;&gt; Yes. &gt;&gt; And then what happens?
&gt;&gt;是的。 &gt;&gt;然後會發生什麼事？
&gt;&gt; Well, we create the quantity variable.
&gt;&gt;嗯， 我們建立了數量變數。
&gt;&gt; Right.
&gt;&gt; 對的。
&gt;&gt; It is initialized to value two.
&gt;&gt;初始數值為 2。
&gt;&gt; And we
&gt;&gt;對的。 &gt;&gt;我們
update it to three cups of coffee.
把它更新為三杯咖啡。
&gt;&gt; And then when the increment method ends, then what happens?
&gt;&gt;當增量方法結束， 那麼會發生什麼事？
&gt;&gt; Well, then the variable gets destroyed.
&gt;&gt;嗯， 那麼變數會被銷毀。
[SOUND] &gt;&gt; Okay, so
[聲音] &gt;&gt;好的，
when I press the plus button again [SOUND] the increment method gets called
當我再次按「加號」按鈕 [聲音]增量方法
in our code- &gt;&gt; And
在我們的代碼裡被呼叫 - &gt;&gt;而且
then we create a quantity variable.
然後我們建立了一個數量變數。
&gt;&gt; Oh, wow.
&gt;&gt;哦，嘩。
Another one magically appeared.
另一個像奇蹟般出現。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, a brand new one.
&gt;&gt;是的，一個全新的。
&gt;&gt; Okay. &gt;&gt; And it's initialized to two, and
&gt;&gt;好的。 &gt;&gt;它的初始值為 2，
then we update it to three.
然後我們把它更新為 3。
&gt;&gt; And then the increment method ends again, and then what happens?
&gt;&gt;然後增量法再次結束， 跟著會發生什麼？
&gt;&gt; The variable gets destroyed.
&gt;&gt;變數被銷毀。
[SOUND] What we really need is a global variable.
[聲音]我們真正需要的是 一個全域變數。
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah.
&gt;&gt;哦，是的。
A variable that can be accessed by any, and all, pieces of code inside our app.
一個可任由我們應用程式內的 部份及全部代碼存取的變數。
&gt;&gt; Exactly, like any method, the increment method or
&gt;&gt;沒錯，像任何方法， 增量方法或
the decrement method.
減量方法。
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm. &gt;&gt; So we create
&gt;&gt;嗯。 &gt;&gt;所以我們建立
a global variable like this.
一個像這樣的全域變數，
It's still the quantity variable.
它仍是數量變數。
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm. &gt;&gt; But now it's global.
&gt;&gt;嗯。 &gt;&gt;但現在它是全域的。
&gt;&gt; So after a method finishes executing,
&gt;&gt;所以方法完成執行後，
it doesn't get destroyed.
它不會被破壞。
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's use this in our code next.
&gt;&gt;好吧， 讓我們在下一個代碼中使用。
&gt;&gt; The problem in our app is that if I hit the + button a bunch of times,
這個應用程式的問題是， 即使我按下 +按鈕數次，
the number of cups of coffee never increases beyond 3.
咖啡杯數 也不能超過3。
The reason is because the + button triggers the increment method.
原因是 +按鈕 觸發增量法。
In this method, we always create a new quantity variable, and
在這方法中，我們總是 建立一個新的數量變數，
initialize it to 2.
並初始化為2。
So when we update the quantity, it's always set to 3.
所以，當我們更新數量時， 它總是設定為 3。
This method has no memory of the fact that I already called it before
這方法對於之前所呼叫的事實 並沒有記憶，
by clicking on the + button, and that I'm already displaying 3 cups of coffee.
通過點擊+按鈕， 經已顯示 3 杯咖啡，
It has no idea that I want 4 cups now.
而它不知道現在我要 4 杯。
In the old code, we declared a local variable for quantity in the increment
在舊代碼中，我們為增量法中的數量 宣告一個區域變數，
method and a local variable for quantity in the decrement method.
也為減量法中的數量
The reason why we can declare a variable with the same name twice is
我們能夠兩次宣告 具有相同名稱的變數是因為
because they are in different variable scopes.
它們位於 不同的變數可視範圍。
This is the scope of the quantity variable declared in
這是增量方法中所宣告的
the increment method.
數量變數的範圍。
Within these bounds we can refer to the quantity and update the quantity.
在這些範圍內，我們可以提及 數量並更新數量。
But outside of these bounds,
但在這些範圍外，
other methods would not know about this quantity variable.
其他方法將不知道 這個數量變量。
You would get an unresolved symbol error because
你會見到一個未解決的 符號錯誤，
other methods wouldn't know about this variable.
是因為其他方法未能 知道這個變數。
Similarly, this is the variable scope for
同樣地，這是減量法中 所宣告的
the local quantity variable declared in the decrement method.
區域數量變數的 變數範圍。
Within this method, you can display the variable and update the variable, but
在這方法中，你能夠顯示 變數及更新變數，
beyond the bounds of this scope, you can't reference it.
但是超出此範圍的界限， 就不能引用。
In the updated code with a global variable,
在包含全域變數的 更新代碼中，
this is what it would look like.
這就是它的樣子。
Instead of declaring the quantity variable in the increment method,
不要在增量法中 宣告數量變數，
we've pulled it out to be declared at the top of the main activity.
我們已經將它拿出來 放在主要活動的頂部宣告。
It's declared within the opening and closing braces of the main activity.
它於主要活動的左大括號 及右大括號內宣告。
So anything inside the main activity will know about the quantity variable.
因此，主要活動裡的任何事情 都會知道數量變數。
This is the variable scope for this global quantity variable.
這是此全域數量變數 的變數範圍。
All the methods and other variables in the main activity
所有方法及 主要活動內的其他變數
can now refer to the quantity, and also update it.
現時可以參照數量， 並且更新它。
So the increment method updates the quantity variable, and also displays it.
因此，增量法更新 數量變數，並顯示它，
And the decrement method also updates the quantity and displays it, and
而減量法也可更新 數量及顯示它，
the quantity always refers back to the global variable here.
而數量總可以重提 這裡的全域變數，
The advantage of pulling it out into a single global variable is now we have
把它拉出來放進 單一全域變數的好處是
a single source of truth for how many cups of coffee the user wants.
現在我們能夠從單一的真值來源 知道用戶要多少杯咖啡。
Even if we've increased the number of coffees a bunch of times,
即使我們多次增加咖啡杯數，
then if we decrease the number of coffees,
然後減少咖啡杯數，
then it'll just use the last known value of the quantity.
它仍只會使用 最後一個的已知數量值。
Before it was weird that we had two quantity variables, because those
我們有兩個數量變數 是很奇怪的事情，是因為
two variables could get out of sync, and the user ends up only seeing one value.
這兩個變數未能同步， 而用戶只看到一個數值。
So it makes sense to have one single source of truth,
因此，真值來自單一的來源 是合理的，
a global variable to keep track of the number of coffees ordered.
使用一個全域變數來追踪 咖啡的定購數量。
You might wonder why we don't just make everything be a global variable and
你可能會問我們為什麼不把 所有一切設定為一個全域變數，
have it solve all our problems.
以便解決所有問題。
You really don't want to make a variable global unless there's a real need
其實你真的不需要一個全域變數， 除非有真正的需要
that other things in the main activity need to reference that variable for.
使主要活動裡的其他事情 需要引用變數。
If you only need to use a method within the context of a single method,
如果在一個方法的範圍內， 只需要使用一個方法，
you should just keep it a local variable.
你就應該把它保持為 一個區域變數。
It's sort of like having a secret.
這有點像一個秘密。
You only tell people on a need to know basis.
你告訴別人 只需要他了解的事情。
Similarly, you only want to reveal variables
同樣地，你只需要透露
that other people absolutely must know about in order for the app to work.
其他人必須知道的變數， 使應用程式運作。
In the MainActivity in the increment method,
在增量法的主要活動中，
I'm going to copy this line of code that declares the quantity variable.
我要複製這行代碼 以宣告數量變數。
I just hit Cmd+X, or it's Ctrl+X to cut.
我只需按 Cmd+X， 或者按 Ctrl+X 以剪下，
And then at the top of the main activity class, I'm going to paste it.
然後在主要活動類別的頂部 將其貼上。
This will be pasted right after the opening breaks of the main activity.
這將會在主要活動的 左括號的旁邊貼上。
Notice that it is outside the braces of other methods.
要注意，它是位於 其他方法的括號外面。
Otherwise, if it was inside the braces of a method,
否則，如果它位於 一個方法的括號裡面，
it would be considered a local variable.
它將被視為一個區域變數。
Quantity is now a global variable within the MainActivity class.
現在數量是一個主要活動類別裡 的全域變數。
We'll learn more about classes in the next lesson.
在下一課，我們將會 進一步了解類別。
The MainActivity is a class that contains methods and variables.
主要活動是一個類別， 包含方法及變數。
Now, any method in the MainActivity can refer to this quantity variable.
現在，主要活動內的任何方法 都可以引用此數量變數。
So this increment method just updates the quantity and displays it.
所以這個增量法 會更新數量並顯示它。
Notice that a global variable has a purple font color for the variable name.
要注意，一個全域變數的 變數名為紫色字體。
If it's a local variable, the font color is black for the variable name.
如果它是一個區域變數， 變數名的字體顏色則為黑色。
So that's how you can tell the difference between local and
所以，你可以看出 全域變數及區域變數
global variables.
的區別。
Speaking of local variables, we want to get rid of this local variable in
說到區域變數，我們要 清除減量法中的區域變數，
the decrement method, because we want to use the global quantity variable.
因為我們要使用 全域數量變數。
The variable name in these methods must match the global variable name, exactly.
在這些方法中的變數名 必須跟全域變數名完全匹配。
If I said quantities here, it would give an error because
如果在這裡我說數量， 就會出現錯誤，
quantities is not defined as a local or a global variable anywhere.
因為數量未被定義為 區域或全域變數。
And I'll undo that so that it works again.
我會把它復原 使它再次運作。
If I run the app, let's see what happens.
我嘗試運行應用程式， 看看發生什麼事情。
The app starts off at a quantity of 2.
應用程式設定數量為 2。
If I hit the + button, it actually increases.
如果我按 +按鈕， 它真的增加了。
If I hit the- button, it actually decreases.
如果我按 -按鈕， 它真的減少了。
That's pretty awesome.
真的很棒。
We've succeeded in building our quantity picker.
我們成功地建設 數量選擇器。
Now, I want you to be able to build this on your phone so you can increase it or
現在，我希望你能夠建立它 到你的手機上，這樣可以增加或
decrease it as much as you want to your heart's desire.
減少數量， 就如你心中所想。
We've included a link to the MainActivity code for you to reference.
這裡包含主要活動代碼的連結， 以供你參考。
I'd rather have you type it out yourself by following this video
我寧願你按照這條影片 自行輸入，
instead of copying and pasting the code.
而不是複製及貼上代碼。
That way, you'll be able to create global variables on your own
這樣將來你才能夠 自行創建
in the future.
全域變數。
I'm going to attach the debugger so
我在此附上調試器，
we can see carefully what's happening with the quantity variable.
我們可以小心看到 數量變數所發生的事情。
I'm going to add breakpoints in the increment and decrement methods and
我要在增量法及減量法 添加斷點，
then run the debugger.
然後運行調試器。
When I hit the + button, then this breakpoint triggers.
當我按下 +按鈕，
Before this line of code has even executed,
在這行代碼執行前，
we see that the global quantity variable already exists with a value
我們看到全域變數 已經存有數值 2 ，
of 2 because of this line of code up here.
是因為這行代碼。
If I set to the next line, then this line has finished executing and
如果我設置到下一行， 那麼這行已經執行完畢，
we've increased the quantity up to 3.
而數量已增加到最多為 3。
I can hit resume so that the app updates to a quantity of 3.
我能夠按下重新開始， 這樣應用程式就會更新數量為 3。
If I hit the + button again, then before I've even executed this line of code,
如果我再次點擊 +按鈕， 然後執行這行代碼，
we already have the global quantity variable set to a value of 3.
我們已經把全域變數的 數值設置為 3。
That was the last known quantity we had before, and it sill remembers it.
這是最後一個已知數量， 而且它仍記得這個數值。
If i increase the quantity by 1,
如果我把數量增加 1，
then the global quantity variable has a variable of 4 now.
那麼全域數量變數 現在變為 4。
I can hit resume to update the screen with 4.
我能夠按下重新開始， 更新屏幕為 4。
Now, we can see that every time the increment method is called ,we can
現在，我們可以看到 每次增量方法被呼叫時，
actually continue to build off of the existing quantity value.
事實上我們可以繼續 建立現有數量值。
Let's see how it interacts with the decrement method.
讓我們來看看它怎樣 跟減量法相互作用。
If I hit the- button, then this breakpoint triggers.
如果我按下 -按鈕， 那麼這斷點就會觸發。
The global quantity variable has a value of 4,
全域數量變數的 數值為 4，
which is what we last left off with.
這是我們上次離開時的數值。
If I decrease the quantity by 1 than it goes down to 3 cups of coffee.
如果我把數量減少 1 那麼變為 3杯咖啡。
And I can display that on the screen and it changes to 3.
在屏幕上就會顯示， 數量更改為3。
With a single global variable for quantity, the increment and
隨著一個全域數量變數， 增量法及減量法
decrement methods can now increase or
現在可以增加或
decrease the number of coffees by 1 based on the latest value of quantity.
減少咖啡的1 杯數量， 以數量的最新值為基礎。
Now, it's your turn, go ahead and
現在，輪到你，
replace the 2 local variables with 1 global variable.
用1 個全域變數 更換 2 個區域變數。
Then, use a debugger to verify that the quantity variable is actually
然後，使用調試器來驗證 數量變數實際上
updating as expected.
是否正如預期那樣更新。
Once your quantity picker works, go ahead and do a little happy dance.
一旦你的數量選擇器順利運作， 繼續努力，開心跳一下舞。
And then you can try to experiment a little bit.
然後繼續嘗試 進行一點點實驗。
What happens if you have a different initial quantity value, like 0?
如果有一個不同的初始值，如0 這將會發生什麼事情？
Or try doubling the quantity each time the + button is pressed.
或者嘗試按下 + 按鈕時 每次增加一倍的數量。
Or halving the quantity each time the- button is pressed.
或者嘗試按下 - 按鈕時 每次減少一半的數量。
Feel free to experiment with whatever you're curious about.
隨意試驗 任何你感到好奇的事。
If you ever wondered, what would happen if I do this or that?
你有沒有想過， 如果我做這做那，將會發生什麼事？
Those are sometimes some of the best learning moments,
這是一些最好的學習時光，
because they're unexpected.
因為它們往往是意想不到的。
When you're done check these boxes to continue.
當你完成時 單擊這些框格以繼續。